Guide to the Edward Northup Hay Papers 1914-1958
Edward Northup Hay Papers
- "The Analysis and Description of High-Level Jobs", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Personnel, January, 1953. 12 pp
- "Reviewing Expense Accounts: A Study in Character", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Management Review, July, 1952. pp. 455-456
- "Banks, No Less Than Industry Have Communications Problems", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Bankers Monthly, April, 1952. p. 38+
- "The Profile Method of High-Level Job Evaluation", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Personnel, Vol. 28, No. 2, 1951. 11 pp
- "Aptitude Tests Reduce Operating Costs.", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  (unpublished) 6 p
- "Investigation of the Use of Tests as a Predictor of Leadership and Group Effectiveness in a Job Evaluation Situation", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Journal of Social Psychology, Vol. 38, 1953. pp. 109-119
- "Predicting Success in Routine Bank Work", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Banking, June, 1951. 2 pp
- "Prediction of Clerical Success in a Life Insurance Company - 1951." (Box 5, Folder 30)
  (mimeographed) May, 1951. 4 pp
- "Validating Clerical Tests in a Branch Bank.", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  (mimeographed) April, 1951. 2 pp
- "Efficiency of Bank Bookkeeping Departments.", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- "Mental Ability Tests in Clerical Selection", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 35, No. 4, August, 1951. pp. 250-251
- Analysis and Evaluation of Executive Positions, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Berkeley: California Personnel Management Association. 12 pp
- "The Bethel Way of Acquiring Group Skills", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 35, No. 5, October, 1956. pp. 178-181
- "Some Problems Faced by Corporation Executives in Connection with Executive Salaries.", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  (draft for Harvard Business Review) January, 1957. 11 pp
- "Something Has Been Done About Developing Salary Standards for Executive Positions.", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  (mimeographed) April, 1957. 8 pp
- "Overtime Pay for Engineers", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 36, No. 3, August, 1957. pp. 90-92.
- "A Simple Method of Recording Paired Comparisons", 1958 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 42, No. 2, 1958. pp. 139-140
- "Civil Liberties Union Shadow-Boxes on Compulsory Unionism", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Foreman's Digest, August, 1956. pp. 17-19
- The Guide Chart-Profile Method of Job-Man Evaluation, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  New York: American Management Association, 8 pp
- "Employee Relations in England", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 35, No. 1, May, 1956. pp. 16-20
- "Good Salary Administration.", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  (mimeographed) May, 1956. 7 pp.
- "Effective Salary Administration.", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  (mimeographed) March, 1956. 4 pp.
- "A New Method of Job Evaluation", 1954 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Personnel, July, 1954. 11 pp
- "Comparative Validities in Clerical Testing", 1954 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 38, No. 5, 1954. pp. 291-301
- "Bank Salary Administration for Employees and Officers.", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  (mimeographed) 8 pp
- "Your Boss is Your Training Director", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 35, No. 6, November, 1956. pp. 220-221
- "Cutting Correspondence Costs" (Box 5, Folder 32)
  American Business, 5pp
- "Predicting Success in Routine Bank Work." (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (unpublished), 9 pp
- Current Problems in Wage and Salary Administration. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  Berkeley: California Personnel Management Association, no date. 7 pp.
- "The Guide Chart-Profile Method: An Explanation." (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (mimeographed), 10 pp.
- "Three Studies in Intra-Group Rating." (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (unpublished), 15 pp
- "Do You Need a Systems and Procedures Section?" (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (unpublished), 6 pp
- "Job Evaluation Reliability." (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (mimeographed), 13 pp
- "Practical Rating Plans" (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (unknown publication), pp. 17-29
- "A Battery of Tests for Clerical Aptitude." (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (unpublished), 16 pp
- "Some Overlooked Responsibilities of Management Toward Employees." (Box 5, Folder 32)
  (mimeographed), 9 pp